Charlie Van Norman

charlievannorman.com (650) 440-5445

Creator, hustler, developer, and leader; I work well with small agile teams, and specialize in AR and VR applications for business.

At my previous ed-tech startup, I cultivated a diverse skill set to meet company goals. My accomplishments there fall under four roles:

BRAND MANAGER

- Successfully developed and launched 2 math games that resulted in 25,000 users over 4 years
- Presented at math ed conferences including CMC, TEKS, EdSurge, and San Mateo, Los Altos school districts
- Hosted 25+ user test events with local partners including Hacker Dojo, Coder Dojo, Hack the Future, and after school programs
- Co-managed a Kickstarter pre-order and merchandise campaign raising \$48,000
- Hired and managed 8 employees and interns

CREATIVE DIRECTOR

- Defined a new style of educational gameplay, merging object based sandbox play and elementary math
- Designed a linear story driven game experience through multiple math subjects
- Designed mechanics to be approachable and playful without any overt explanation
- Designed the core mechanics to reveal emergent properties including state machines, sequence generation, Pascal's triangle, and multivariate algeb
- Designed an in-game level editor
- Directed and produced 3 product showcase videos

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT

- Closed 5 distribution partners including HSBC, EduGamesKart, Educents,
 TeacherGaming, Filament
- Added two math celebrities to advisory board, Dan Meyer and Jo Boaler, which led to 200+ teacher sales and gave credibility and recognition to our brand
- Added 2 math department leads to our board, leading to several school partnerships and 3 investors
- Visited 50 schools in Bay Area to build our initial client base and teacher relationships for testing
- Reached out to 40+ journalists who wrote 7 articles including GameSpot, Huffington Post and EdWeek

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Unity3D C# front-end game interactions, mechanics and behaviors across 200+ unique game objects
- Unity3D C# back-end game architecture layer to standardize game asset properties and interactions
- Full web stack using AWS, ubuntu, Apache, Django, Python, MySQL, HTML, jquery/js, css
- Wrote a javascript integration layer to propagate game actions and analytics to Django/SQL
- Built an in-game editor layer for live content creation and sharing
- Wrote command line tools for one-button deployment and testing

EXPERIENCE

I help startups to find b2b market opportunities for VR and AR, and to discover, spec, design, and build applications in the space.

2016 - 2017 Co-founder, Super Math World - Imaginary Number Co

- Developed a tool for creating, editing and sharing levels
- Designed and built the game mechanics and game architecture
- Built the full web stack on javascript, python/django/AWS
- Formed key partnerships with distributors and math celebrities

2015 Contractor, Mouse Brain Explorer - 3Scan

VR mouse brain navigation game for Exploratorium

2013 - 2016 Tech program director - Synapse Middle School

- Directed the afterschool technical program for three quarters
- Designed curriculum for and managed a math summer camp

2013 - 2016 Co-founder, Mathbreakers - Imaginary Number Co

- Co-founded the company and recruited a team
- Prototyped and tested early games to find product market fit
- Traveled to local schools to establish our first customer base

2012 Entrepreneur, Start Up Chile

Built a startup resources hub for finding investors, local events, incubators, competitiors, customers, and employees

2011 Contractor, Code Hero - Primer Labs

Lead developer and designer of Code Hero, an FPS game that teaches javascript by modifying the game itself during gameplay using eval()

2010 Founder - Fractal Games

- Hired and managed art team
- Partnered with programmers for game logic
- Produced two iOS titles, Santa's Last Stand and Bank Defense

2009 Property Manager - Alexander Forrest

I rehabilitated two failing complexes with 60 and 110 units, including lease up, rent collections, repairs, materials budgeting, and hiring and managing staff, leading to the profitability of both properties and the sale of one property.

EDUCATION

2010 - 2012 San Francisco State

M.B.A. Entrepreneurship program (dropped out to found a company)

2010 Urban Land Institue

Real Estate Development Program

2001 - 2007 Cal Poly Pomona

B.S. International Business

2 years Mechanical Engineering + Physics classes

2002 - 2003 Beijing, China

International student program Taught English on the side

2006 Salamanca, Spain

Immersive Spanish program and business classes